Guide to the City Planning Commission, Pittsburgh, Pa. Records, 1928-1962 AIS.1976.17
ULS Archives & Special Collections
City Planning Commission, Pittsburgh, Pa. Records
1928-1962
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Pittsburgh (Pa.). City Planning Commission
AIS.1976.17
5.25 Linear Feet (4 record center boxes and 1 document case)
The City Planning Commission is responsible for the city's development, through policy and development review and through administration of the zoning ordinance. During the 1940s and 1950s, the commission devoted its energy to the redevelopment of areas that had been full of vacant or sub-standard housing and factory buildings, and the improvement and construction of major thoroughfares. This collection contains minutes, special reports, and other records of the City of Pittsburgh Planning Commission, chiefly from the years 1940-1960.
History
The City Planning Commission is responsible for the City of Pittsburgh's development, through policy and development review and through administration of the zoning ordinance. The Department of City Planning is responsible for community development by facilitating community planning processes and supporting community based and technical assistance programs. The department was created in 1927, but it was not until the Second World War that it received the initiative to alter the appearance of Pittsburgh. On February 4, 1942, Mayor Cornelius D. Scully gave the City Planning Commission the authority to take the lead in planning for post-war construction and renewal. During that time many considered the city to be in a dilapidated state because of the lack of enforcement of city codes and ordinances during the depression. The Commission devoted its energy to the redevelopment of areas that had been full of vacant or sub-standard housing and factory buildings, and the improvement and construction of major thoroughfares. Information about their current activities can be found at http://www.city.pittsburgh.pa.us/cp/.
Some of the other agencies that the City Planning Commission worked with included: the Department of Public Works, the Urban Redevelopment Authority, the Better Traffic Committee, the Civic Club of Allegheny County, the Allegheny Conference on Community Development, and the Pittsburgh Housing Association (ACTION-Housing, Inc.). Records from these last two organizations form a significant part of this collection.
Jesse Paul Watson was an active member of the City Planning Commission throughout the 1940's and 1950's, and replaced Frederick Bigger as chairman in 1954. Watson worked in the Bureau of Business Research at the University of Pittsburgh since the 1930s and was involved in several other initiatives to revitalize Pittsburgh, most notably the Allegheny Conference on Community Development, beginning in 1943; and the Pittsburgh Housing Association (now ACTION-Housing, Inc.), throughout the 1950s.
The Allegheny Conference on Post-War Community Planning was formed during World War II by prominent citizens of Allegheny County. These included Richard King Mellon, President of the Pittsburgh Regional Planning Association, and Robert Doherty, President of Carnegie Institute of Technology. Their aim was to coordinate local efforts to improve transportation and industry. In 1944 it was incorporated as the Allegheny Conference on Community Development. More information can be found at http://www.alleghenyconference.org.
The Pittsburgh Housing Association was active by 1928, and is still operating under the name of ACTION-Housing, Inc., which it adopted in 1957. It maintains a website at http://www.actionhousing.org/. The purpose of the Association was to promote the development of good quality, affordable housing for people living in Pittsburgh.
Scope and Content Notes
Further scope and content notes are available at the series level.
Arrangement
The collection consists of six series:
Series I: Minutes and Special Reports
Series II: General Operations
Series III: Housing
Series IV: Traffic and Roads
Series V: Papers of J.P. Watson
Series VI: Redevelopment and Zoning
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Minutes and reports were donated to the University Library System in 1976.
The remainder of the collection was donated in 2001.
Previous Citation
City Planning Commission, Pittsburgh, Pa. Records, 1928-1962, AIS.1976.17, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
Minutes and Reports of the City of Pittsburgh Planning Commission, 1940-1959, AIS 76:17, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
Related Material
Additional collections at the Archives Service Center relating to Ireland or the Irish in Pittsburgh include: ACTION-Housing, Inc. Records, 1957-1992, AIS.2001.11; Allegheny Conference on Community Development Collection, 1944-1993, AIS.1973.04; Housing Authority of the City of Pittsburgh Records, 1937-1953, AIS.1966.08; David Leo Lawrence Papers, 1959-1966, AIS.1978.15; Marjorie and J. Warren Matson Papers, 1942-1980, AIS.1984.17.
Urban renewal -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Transportation; Government; Pittsburgh (Pa.); Traffic engineering -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Zoning -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; City planning -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh Metropolitan Area; Pittsburgh (Pa.) -- Politics and government; Housing -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Pittsburgh Housing Association; Watson, J. P. (Jesse Paul); Woods, C. Ronal; Action-Housing, Inc; Lawrence, David Leo; Allegheny Conference on Post-War Community Planning (Pa.); Bigger, Frederick, Thomas; Buente, Willard F.; Hovde, Brynjolf Jakob; Pittsburgh (Pa.). City Planning Commission; Allegheny Conference on Community Development (Pa.)
- Minutes and Special Reports, 1940-1959; I.
  Scope and Content Notes
  This series contains the meeting minutes for the commission generally, from the years 1940-1959 as well as special reports. Minutes from 1940-1959 are bound in ten volumes. Volume six is split between box one and two.
  - Minutes (Box 1, Volume 1-6)
  - Minutes, 1940-195 (Box 2, Volume 6-10)
  - Minutes, January-February 1960 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Special Reports, 1945-1951 (Box 2, Volume 11-12)
- General operational records and subject files, II.
  This series contains records of the general operations of the commission and the Pittsburgh Master Plan, as well as other projects. Activities of various committees are represented, including the replacement of the Planning Director in 1950. The records filed under "Finance" are not very extensive. Minutes in this series are from the Committee on General Plans, which met separately from the commission as a whole.
  - Administration and personnel records, 1939-1955 (Box 3, Folder 1-3)
  - Special Committee on Administration, 1948-1950 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Finance, 1943-1945 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Committee on Legislation-Staff Reports, 1942, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Post-War Planning, 1942-1943 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Pittsburgh Plan, 1944-1949 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Long-range planning, 1956-1959 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Committee on General Plans: minutes, 1954-1959 (Box 3, Folder 10-13)
  - Committee on General Plans: minutes Jan.-Feb. 1960, Ad-Hoc Committee on Administration: minutes, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Municipal Outdoor Amphitheatre, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Fort Pitt, 1942 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Fire Station Study, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Space Use Inventory of Central Business District-Field Survey Manual, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Land Use, 1937, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Miscellaneous, 1942-1945 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Housing, III.
  This series contains memos, articles, clippings, and other documents of the commission's involvement with housing and the planning of lots in Pittsburgh from 1943 to 1951. The series also contains copies of all records generated or used specifically by the Pittsburgh Housing Association (PHA) as kept by Dr. Watson, from 1948 to 1959. These are arranged chronologically and include meeting minutes, memos, correspondence, budget proposals, and public relations writings. Among other things, the records document the efforts to secure funding to the PHA from the Community Chest, and the change in name from Pittsburgh Housing Association to ACTION-Housing, Inc. Also included is a resource unit published by the PHA for use in Pittsburgh area schools. Issues of the PHA newsletter Housing News from March 1953 through December 1955 can be found in ais Journals in the Archives Service Center.
  - Housing, 1943-1952 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Committee on Plan of Lots: Staff Reports, 1943-1951 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Housing Evaluation Surveys, 1950-1951 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Monograph: The Status of Housing of Negroes in Pittsburgh, City of Pittsburgh Commission on Human Relations, November 1958, presented to Planning Commission by C. Ronal Woods, March 13, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Pittsburgh Housing Association: Charter and By-Laws, 1928, Reports, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - PHA: Program, 1948-1950 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - PHA, 1949-1959 (Box 3, Folder 27-35)
  - A Resource Unit on Housing by PHA & the Western Pennsylvania Council for the Social Studies, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 36)
- Traffic and Roads, IV.
  This series holds records of dealings with the Bureau of Traffic Planning and Better Traffic Committee, and the construction of many new motorways around the Pittsburgh area. Specific roads represented include: 22-30 or Penn-Lincoln Parkway, Brookline Boulevard, Crosstown Thoroughfare, and Ohio River Boulevard. Willard F. Buente, the chief engineer of the Department of City Planning, was a major participant in these projects.
  - Traffic, 1937 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Traffic, 1939-1950 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Report from Better Traffic Committee, 1942 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Major Highway Projects: General, 1941-1944 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - 22-30 or Penn-Lincoln Parkway, 1942-1946 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Brookline Boulevard, 1947 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Crosstown Thoroughfare, 1942-1944 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Ohio River Boulevard, 1943-1944 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Road maps and Plans, 1940-1948 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Business papers of Jesse Paul Watson, V.
  This series contains records accumulated by Dr. Watson during his tenure with the commission as a member and as chairman. The papers mostly consist of correspondence, memos, and reports. The records from the Allegheny Conference include correspondence with members of the Conference, surveys, newspaper clippings, and meeting minutes from the various committees within the Conference.
  - Minutes and Papers, 1.
    - Executive Session Minutes, 1954, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Papers, 1951-1957 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Papers, 1958-1959 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Allegheny Conference, 2.
    - Industrial Inventory, 1946 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Citizen Sponsoring Committee Minutes, 1943-1945 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - General, 1943-1946 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Research Committee, 1944-1946 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Housing Committee, 1944-1946 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Demobilization Committee, 1944 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Development of Skills Committee, 1944 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Health and Welfare Committee, 1944 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Land Use and Zoning Committee, 1943-1944 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Public Improvements Committee, 1943-1944 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Review of PA legislation on Urban Redevelopment & Housing, 1946 (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Redevelopment and Zoning, VI.
  The commission worked closely with the Urban Redevelopment Authority in redeveloping neighborhoods that were deemed to be in need of improvement. Documents produced from these activities are here together with records of the Zoning Committee. Folder 31 contains a zoning map of the city dated 1927. The General files relate to various zoning cases and inquiries. The files for the proposed new zoning ordinances contain drafts of tentative zoning ordinances, news releases, memos, and correspondence between Frederick Bigger and Earl O. Mills, the Staffing Consultant who drafted the new ordinance in 1947. Also included is correspondence from various parties – notably the Civic Club of Allegheny County – about the new ordinance in its various revisions.
  - Proposal for the Redevelopment of Area #3 in 2nd and 3rd Wards, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 24-25)
  - Redevelopment Plan for Area #3, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Redevelopment Plan – East Liberty, Redevelopment Area #10, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Reports on Capital Improvement Requirements, 1957-1961 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Capital Improvement Program, 1957, Progress Report, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Progress Report: Redevelopment & Renewal in Pittsburgh, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Zoning: General, 1942-1956 (Box 4, Folder 31-32)
  - Nursing Homes, 1942-1944 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Proposed Articles of Organization of the Pennsylvania Planning Association, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Zoning: Court Opinions, 1950 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Zoning Committee: Staff Reports and Memoranda, 1954 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Zoning Committee: Staff Reports, 1956-1957 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Draft of New Zoning Ordinance, undated (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Zoning Law, 1941-1950 (Box 4, Folder 39-40)
  - Zoning Law, 1951-1954 (Box 5, Folder 1-2)
  - Proposal for the Redevelopment of Project Area 2A in Area #2 in the 16th (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Proposal for the Redevelopment of Project Area 1-B & 1-C in Area #1, 1st and 2nd Wards, 1949 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Proposal for the Redevelopment of Area #4 & the Partial Redevelopment of Area #5 in the 15th Ward, 1952 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Analysis of Part of the Lower Hill District, 1950, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Analysis of the Lower Hazelwood District, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Oversize Material, VII.
  This material was added to the finiding aid in November 2010.
  - Land Use Data for Pittsburgh, 1st Ward, Chart, 1939 (Map-case 7-7, Folder 1)
  - Land Use Data for Pittsburgh, 2nd Ward, Chart, 1939
  - Land Use Data for Pittsburgh, 3rd Ward, Chart, 1939
  - Land Use Data for Pittsburgh, 4th Ward, Chart, 1939
  - Land Use Data for Pittsburgh, 5th Ward, Chart, 1939
  - Land Use Data for Pittsburgh, 6th Ward, Chart, 1939
  - Land Use Data for Pittsburgh, 7th Ward, Chart, 1939
  - Land Use Data for Pittsburgh, 8th Ward, Chart, 1939
  - Land Use Data for Pittsburgh, 9th Ward, Chart, 1939
  - Land Use Data for Pittsburgh, 10th Ward, Chart, 1939
  - Land Use Data for Pittsburgh, 11th Ward, Chart, 1939
  - Land Use Data for Pittsburgh, 12th Ward, Chart, 1939 (Map-case 7-7, Folder 2)
  - Land Use Data for Pittsburgh, 13th Ward, Chart, 1939
  - Land Use Data for Pittsburgh, 14th Ward, Chart, 1939
  - Land Use Data for Pittsburgh, 15th Ward, Chart, 1939
  - Land Use Data for Pittsburgh, 16th Ward, Chart, 1939
  - Land Use Data for Pittsburgh, 17th Ward, Chart, 1939
  - Land Use Data for Pittsburgh, 18th Ward, Chart, 1939
  - Land Use Data for Pittsburgh, 19th Ward, Chart, 1939
  - Land Use Data for Pittsburgh, 20th Ward, Chart, 1939
  - Land Use Data for Pittsburgh, 21st Ward, Chart, 1939 (Map-case 7-7, Folder 3)
  - Land Use Data for Pittsburgh, 22nd Ward, Chart, 1939
  - Land Use Data for Pittsburgh, 23rd Ward, Chart, 1939
  - Land Use Data for Pittsburgh, 24th Ward, Chart, 1939
  - Land Use Data for Pittsburgh, 25th Ward, Chart, 1939
  - Land Use Data for Pittsburgh, 26th Ward, Chart, 1939
  - Land Use Data for Pittsburgh, 27th Ward, Chart, 1939
  - Land Use Data for Pittsburgh, 28th Ward, Chart, 1939
  - Land Use Data for Pittsburgh, 29th Ward, Chart, 1939
  - Land Use Data for Pittsburgh, 30th Ward, Chart, 1939
  - Land Use Data for Pittsburgh, 31st Ward, Chart, 1939
  - Land Use Data for Pittsburgh, 32nd Ward, Chart, 1939
  - Land Use Data for Pittsburgh, Area in Square Feet, by Census Tract, Chart, 1939 (Map-case 7-7, Folder 4)
  - Land Use Data for Pittsburgh, Area in Square Feet, Zoning, Chart, 1939
  - Land Use Data for Pittsburgh, Area in Square Feet, by Ward, Chart, 1939
  - Land Use Data for Pittsburgh, Slope and Zoning, Wards 1-32, Chart, 1939
  - Land Use Data for Pittsburgh, Index, Wards 1-32, Maps
  - Land Use Data for Pittsburgh, Index, Wards 14-32, Maps
  - 1940 Census Map, Dwellings, Person per room, by block, Sheet 1 of 3, October 1944 (Map-case 7-7, Folder 5)
  - 1940 Census Map, Dwellings, Person per room, by block, Sheet 2 of 3, Ocotber 1944
  - 1940 Census Map, Dwellings, Person per room, by block, Sheet 3 of 3, October 1944
  - 1940 Census Map, Dwellings, Average rent, by block, Sheet 1 of 3, October 1944
  - 1940 Census Map, Dwellings, Average rent, by block, Sheet 2 of 3, October 1944
  - 1940 Census Map, Dwellings, Average rent, by block, Sheet 3 of 3, October 1944
  - 1940 Census Map, Dwellings, Needing major repair, by block, Sheet 1 of 3, October 1944
  - 1940 Census Map, Dwellings, Needing major repair, by block, Sheet 2 of 3, October 1944
  - 1940 Census Map, Dwellings, Needing major repair, by block, Sheet 3 of 3, October 1944
  - 1940 Census Map, Dwellings, Owner Occupied, by block, Sheet 1 of 3, October 1944; 45.
  - 1940 Census Map, Dwellings, Owner Occupied, by block, Sheet 2 of 3, October 1944
  - 1940 Census Map, Dwellings, Owner Occupied, by block, Sheet 3 of 3, October 1944
  - 1940 Census Map, Dwellings, Year built, Median year, by block, Sheet 1 of 3, October 1944
  - 1940 Census Map, Dwellings, Year built, Median year, by block, Sheet 2 of 3, October 1944
  - 1940 Census Map, Dwellings, Year built, Median year, by block, Sheet 3 of 3, October 1944
  - 1940 Census Map, Dwellings, Built from 1900-1920, by block, Sheet 1 of 2, October 1944
  - 1940 Census Map, Dwellings, Built from 1900-1920, by block, Sheet 2 of 2, October 1944
  - Average rent, by blocks, for Pittsburgh, Pa., Part 1 of 8, Map, 1940 (Map-case 7-7, Folder 6)
  - Average rent, by blocks, for Pittsburgh, Pa., Part 2 of 8, Map, 1940
  - Average rent, by blocks, for Pittsburgh, Pa., Part 3 of 8, Map, 1940
  - Average rent, by blocks, for Pittsburgh, Pa., Part 4 of 8, Map, 1940
  - Average rent, by blocks, for Pittsburgh, Pa., Part 5 of 8, Map, 1940
  - Average rent, by blocks, for Pittsburgh, Pa., Part 7 of 8, Map, 1940
  - Average rent, by blocks, for Pittsburgh, Pa., Part 8 of 8, Map, 1940
  - Major repairs and bathing equipment, by blocks, for Pittsburgh, Pa., Part 1 of 8, Map, 1940
  - Major repairs and bathing equipment, by blocks, for Pittsburgh, Pa., Part 2 of 8, Map, 1940
  - Major repairs and bathing equipment, by blocks, for Pittsburgh, Pa., Part 3 of 8, Map, 1940
  - Major repairs and bathing equipment, by blocks, for Pittsburgh, Pa., Part 4 of 8, Map, 1940
  - Major repairs and bathing equipment, by blocks, for Pittsburgh, Pa., Part 5 of 8, Map, 1940
  - Major repairs and bathing equipment, by blocks, for Pittsburgh, Pa., Part 6 of 8, Map, 1940
  - Major repairs and bathing equipment, by blocks, for Pittsburgh, Pa., Part 7 of 8, Map, 1940
  - Major repairs and bathing equipment, by blocks, for Pittsburgh, Pa., Part 8 of 8, Map, 1940
  - Year built, by blocks, for Pittsburgh, Pa., Part 1 of 8, Map, 1940
  - Year built, by blocks, for Pittsburgh, Pa., Part 2 of 8, Map, 1940
  - Year built, by blocks, for Pittsburgh, Pa., Part 3 of 8, Map, 1940
  - Year built, by blocks, for Pittsburgh, Pa., Part 4 of 8, Map, 1940
  - Year built, by blocks, for Pittsburgh, Pa., Part 5 of 8, Map, 1940
  - Year built, by blocks, for Pittsburgh, Pa., Part 6 of 8, Map, 1940
  - Year built, by blocks, for Pittsburgh, Pa., Part 7 of 8, Map, 1940
  - Year built, by blocks, for Pittsburgh, Pa., Part 8 of 8, Map, 1940
  - Nonwhite households, by blocks, for Pitsburgh, Pa., Part 1 of 8, Map, 1940
  - Nonwhite households, by blocks, for Pitsburgh, Pa., Part 2 of 8, Map, 1940
  - Nonwhite households, by blocks, for Pitsburgh, Pa., Part 3 of 8, Map, 1940
  - Nonwhite households, by blocks, for Pitsburgh, Pa., Part 4 of 8, Map, 1940
  - Nonwhite households, by blocks, for Pitsburgh, Pa., Part 5 of 8, Map, 1940
  - Nonwhite households, by blocks, for Pitsburgh, Pa., Part 6 of 8, Map, 1940
  - Nonwhite households, by blocks, for Pitsburgh, Pa., Part 7 of 8, Map, 1940
  - Nonwhite households, by blocks, for Pitsburgh, Pa., Part 8 of 8, Map, 1940
  - Persons per room, by blocks, for Pittsburgh, Pa., Part 1 of 8, Map, 1940
  - Persons per room, by blocks, for Pittsburgh, Pa., Part 2 of 8, Map, 1940
  - Persons per room, by blocks, for Pittsburgh, Pa., Part 3 of 8, Map, 1940
  - Persons per room, by blocks, for Pittsburgh, Pa., Part 4 of 8, Map, 1940
  - Persons per room, by blocks, for Pittsburgh, Pa., Part 5 of 8, Map, 1940
  - Persons per room, by blocks, for Pittsburgh, Pa., Part 6 of 8, Map, 1940
  - Persons per room, by blocks, for Pittsburgh, Pa., Part 7 of 8, Map, 1940
  - Persons per room, by blocks, for Pittsburgh, Pa., Part 8 of 8, Map, 1940
  - Owner occupancy, by blocks, for Pittsburgh, Pa., Part 1 of 8, Map, 1940
  - Owner occupancy, by blocks, for Pittsburgh, Pa., Part 4 of 8, Map, 1940
  - Owner occupancy, by blocks, for Pittsburgh, Pa., Part 5 of 8, Map, 1940
  - Owner occupancy, by blocks, for Pittsburgh, Pa., Part 6 of 8, Map, 1940
  - Owner occupancy, by blocks, for Pittsburgh, Pa., Part 7 of 8, Map, 1940
  - Owner occupancy, by blocks, for Pittsburgh, Pa., Part 8 of 8, Map, 1940
  - Mortgage status, by blocks, for Pittsburgh, Pa., Part 1 of 8, Map, 1940
  - Mortgage status, by blocks, for Pittsburgh, Pa., Part 2 of 8, Map, 1940
  - Mortgage status, by blocks, for Pittsburgh, Pa., Part 3 of 8, Map, 1940
  - Mortgage status, by blocks, for Pittsburgh, Pa., Part 4 of 8, Map, 1940
  - Mortgage status, by blocks, for Pittsburgh, Pa., Part 5 of 8, Map, 1940
  - Mortgage status, by blocks, for Pittsburgh, Pa., Part 6 of 8, Map, 1940
  - Mortgage status, by blocks, for Pittsburgh, Pa., Part 7 of 8, Map, 1940
  - Mortgage status, by blocks, for Pittsburgh, Pa., Part 8 of 8, Map, 1940
  - Groundwork & Inventory for Pittsburgh Plan, Population change, 1930 to 1940, Map, 1944 (Map-case 7-7, Folder 7)
  - Groundwork & Inventory for Pittsburgh Plan, First Aspect, Natural Pattern of Improvement Districts, Map, 1944
  - Groundwork & Inventory for Pittsburgh Plan, Second Aspect, Three Chief Types of Improvement Districts, Map, 1944
  - Groundwork & Inventory for Pittsburgh Plan, Third Aspect, Internediate Areas, Economically Buildable and Unbuildable Land, Map, 1944
  - Groundwork & Inventory for Pittsburgh Plan, Key Map to Identify Natural Pattern of Improvement Districts, Map, 1944
  - Groundwork & Inventory for Pittsburgh Plan, Number of Occupied Dwelling Units Within Each Residential Improvement District, Map, 1944
  - Groundwork & Inventory for Pittsburgh Plan, Population Density, Approximate Number of Families per Gross Acre Within Each Residential Improvement District, Map, 1944
  - Groundwork & Inventory for Pittsburgh Plan, Dwelling Units Within Each Residential Improvement District Built Prior to 1900, Map, 1944
  - Groundwork & Inventory for Pittsburgh Plan, Dwelling Units Within Each Residential Improvement District Which Need Major Repairs or Private Bath or Both, Map, 1944
  - Groundwork & Inventory for Pittsburgh Plan, Dwelling Units Within Each Residential Improvement District Having and Average of 1.51 or More Persons per Room, Map, 1944
  - Groundwork & Inventory for Pittsburgh Plan, Average Monthly Rental of Dwelling Units Within Each Residential Improvement District, Map, 1944
  - Groundwork & Inventory for Pittsburgh Plan, Owner-Occupied Dwelling Units Within Each Residential Improvement District, Map, 1944
  - Groundwork & Inventory for Pittsburgh Plan, Existing Land Uses, Simplified Pattern, City-Wide, Map, 1944
  - Groundwork & Inventory for Pittsburgh Plan, Simplified Pattern of Existing Land Uses Within Each Residential Improvement District, Map, 1944
  - Groundwork & Inventory for Pittsburgh Plan, Simplified Pattern of Existing Land Uses of City Area Exclusive of Residential Improvement Districts, Map, 1944